IRINA SARATOVSKAYA



Frontend Developer

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Date of birth: 26.02.1986 Nationality: Russian

Current residence: Moscow, Russia

CONTACT DETAILS:

☑ saratovskaya.business@gmail.com

e www.irinasaratovskaya.com

PROFILE:

I am a result-oriented professional with 13 years of experience in various areas, including IT and Blockchain projects, working in Business Development & Sales, Software Development, Software Testing and Translation/Localization (English, Korean, and Russian). I have a passion for technologies, and I am open to new opportunities that allow me to work on diverse, challenging projects with bright, interesting colleagues while developing my skills.

EDUCATION:

2003-2008: Russian State Social University (Russia, Moscow)

Department of foreign languages

from Silicon Valley)

Major: Theory and methods of teaching foreign languages and cultures (English, Korean).

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

08/2019 - current: Frontend Development

✓ Self-education: online courses (400+ hours) ✓ Professional mentoring (Senior Developer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Frontend Development

03/2020 - current

- Junior Frontend Developer at a Nutrition Technology startup:
 - ✓ Building responsive layouts using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, etc.
 - ✓ Creating forms, interactive UI components.
 - ✓ Working with state management, Redux, code refactoring.
 - ✓ Using REST API, CRUD, AJAX, Git.
 - ✓ Unit testing (Jest & Enzyme).
- Working on a personal Fitness app (workout programs and tracking).

10/2010: The National Institute of Korean Language (Korea)

Educational Program for Experts in Korean Studies.

Translation, Localization, and Testing (Freelance) 09/2008 - 04/2020

Localization Agencies and Game Development Studios

- Translation & Localization of websites, mobile apps, games, etc. (Korean, English, and Russian).
- Functional & non-functional testing (UI/UX, localization, usability, compatibility, etc.).
- Translation fields: IT, Blockchain, Fintech, marketing & PR, legal, accounting and finance, medicine, etc.

07/2007 - 08/2007: Gwangju University (Korea)

Korean language training and culture experience program.

06/2006 - 09/2006: Changwon National University (Korea)

Korean language training and culture experience program.

AVA Software (yachting IT startup), Singapore

08/2019 - 03/2020

Business Development Manager

Responsibilities:

- Preparing the launch of new software for the yachting industry:
 - ✓ Working with team leads, business partners, and end users to plan, design, and execute pre-release tests.
 - ✓ Designing test cases and scenarios, and executing manual tests.
 - ✓ Providing detailed bug reports to the development team.
- Market research and launch strategy development.
- Promoting and selling software in SEA, Europe, and the USA (B2B).

LANGUAGES:

- ✓ English (fluent)
- √ Korean (fluent)
- √ Russian (native)

Key achievements:

I helped to plan and coordinate the development and launch of the company's flagship product, business proposals, and communication strategy to attract our first clients, and build partnerships with several major companies in the industry.

CFS Digital (Blockchain projects), Estonia

08/2017 - 08/2019

Market Specialist & Business Development Manager

Responsibilities:

- Promotion of Blockchain and Fintech products and services on the global stage (turnkey solutions, ICOs).
- Localization & Testing: websites, UI, presentations, Whitepaper, blogs, etc.
- Working with project founders, developers, and end users to plan and prepare and launch products/ ICOs.

Key achievements:

I helped multiple Blockchain startups adapt their products and services for foreign markets (SEA, Russia, and Europe) and raise over 50,000 BTC on ICOs.

Asia Marine, Ltd. (Luxury Yacht charters), Thailand

11/2016 - 04/2017

Sales Manager

Responsibilities:

- Selling Luxury Yacht charters and coordinating activities within the charter division.
- Preparing promotional materials, managing the company's website.
 Translation of documents, websites, brochures, etc.

Key achievements:

I attracted the Russian market by establishing partnerships with eight major Russian travel agencies and luxury hotels and villas in Phuket. This provided a continuous flow of customers and therefore increased sales by 30%.

VCP Tour Co., Ltd. (Tourist services), Thailand

05/2014 - 10/2016

Sales and Marketing manager

Responsibilities:

- Assisting in developing the company's online booking platform and website from scratch:
 - ✓ Development and execution of software test plans, manual testing.
 - ✓ Documenting software defects and reporting to the team.
 - ✓ Tracking the bug status and communicating with developers.
 - √ Working directly with customers to understand and resolve their needs.
- Preparation and implementation of the system launch strategy.
- Promoting the platform, developing and maintaining relationships with customers and tour suppliers, hotels, car rental agencies, shops, etc.

Key achievements:

I had a key role in developing and localizing the company's products and services (booking system, website, etc.) and attracted the Russian market with which the company had never worked before.

Nuga Medical (Korean medical equipment), Russia

10/2012 - 03/2014

Senior marketing manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

Responsibilities:

- Interpreting & Translation (medical field).
- Organization of dealer conferences, development of ad materials.

Daehong Communications (Marketing & PR), Russia

10/2007 - 09/2012

Account manager/Translator (English, Korean, Russian)

Responsibilities:

- Translation and interpreting.
- Managing key clients, preparation of advertising campaigns.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS:

- JavaScript
- React.js
- Node.js
- HTML, CSS (Bootstrap)
- SQL

TECHNOLOGY TOOLS:

- MS Office
- Git, npm
- SmartCAT
- MemoQ
- SDL Trados Studio

COLLABORATION TOOLS:

- Jira, Trello
- Asana
- Zoho
- Slack, Zoom
- Pipedrive
- Amo CRM

PORTFOLIO:

www.irinasaratovskaya.com